紐約市
這就下去協調搜救工作
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
真的  你怎么做到不吐的
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
閉嘴
Shut up.
伙計
Buddy!
你怎么想的  已達到承載上限了
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
走樓梯吧
Take the stairs.
是啊  別別
Yeah. Stop, stop.
交出箱子  斯塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
交出來
Hand it over.
斯塔克
Stark?
呼吸
Breathe, breathe.
好樣的  巷子里見  我去找點吃的
Good job. Meet me in the alley. I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不走樓梯
No stairs!
洛基呢
Where's Loki?
洛基  洛基
Loki! Loki!
人人影視
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
翻|校|監         惡作劇之草     杏仁斯嘉麗       Eunice
字幕組招新中
請訪問 YYSubs.com
時間軸       知之圓夢  大蔥         后期      吉吉
蒙古  戈壁灘
我是阿斯加德的洛基
I am Loki of Asgard.
我肩負光榮的使命
And I am burdened with glorious purpose.
你是誰
你來我們家干什么
我...
I...
沒事了
Never mind.
別碰那個
Don't touch that.
似乎是標準的時序違規
Appears to be a standard sequence violation.
時間分支進展速度和斜率穩定
Branch is growing at a stable rate and slope.
時間異體已確認
Variant identified.
你說我什么
I beg your pardon.
代表時間變異管理局
On behalf of the Time Variance Authority,
我以侵犯神圣時間線的罪名逮捕你
I hereby arrest you for crimes against the Sacred Timeline.
手舉起來
Hands up.
你跟我們走
You're coming with us.
抱歉  "我們"是誰
I'm sorry. Who's "Us"?
最后機會  時間異體
Last chance, Variant.
今天真的很辛苦了
It's been a very long day,
我受夠了全副武裝的白癡
and I think I've had my fill of idiots in armored suits
對我指手畫腳
telling me what to do,
所以  不好意思  這其實是你們最后的機會
so, if you don't mind, this is actually your last chance.
給我滾吧
Now get out of my way.
你正在以1/16的速度移動
You are now moving at 1/16th speed,
但卻在以實際時間感受疼痛
but feeling all that pain in real time.
重置時間線
Reset the timeline.
-什么種族  -斯庫魯時間異體
- What species? - Variant Skrull.
這是什么地方
What is this place?
我爸可是高盛董事會成員
My dad is on the board of Goldman Sachs.
我一通電話  就讓你的工作私有化
One call and your whole job is privatized.
-好了  -你覺得那怎么樣
- All right. - How'd you like that?
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
-走了  -你在犯下大錯
- Come on. - You're making a terrible mistake.
你犯下了大錯
You're making a big mistake.
-你好  長官  -登記這項證物
- Hello, ma'am, uh... - Log this as evidence.
能至少告訴我這是什么嗎
Can you at least tell me what it is?
是宇宙魔方  務必小心
It's the Tesseract. Be very careful with it.
聽上去好傻
It sounds dumb.
告訴你
Know this.
你敢惹我  后果很嚴重
You cross me, there are deadly consequences.
走著瞧吧
We'll see.
想都別想
Absolutely not.
這可是高檔阿斯加德皮革
This is fine Asgardian leather.
別動
Hold very still.
等一下的
Now, hang on just a minute.
請簽字確認這是你說過的所有的話
Please sign to verify this is everything you've ever said.
什么
What?
這個也要簽
Sign this, too.
什么
這太荒唐了
Oh, this is absurd.
還有這份
And this.
請確認  據你所知
Please confirm to your knowledge
你并非完全的機械體
that you are not a fully robotic being,
出生時是有機體
were born an organic creature,
并擁有在很多文化中被稱為靈魂的東西
and do in fact possess what many cultures would call a soul.
什么  "據我所知"
What? "To my knowledge"?
難道有很多人不知道自己是不是機器人嗎
Do a lot of people not know if they're robots?
感謝你的確認  請往前走
Thank you for confirming. Move through.
如果我真是機器人  可我不知道呢
What if I was a robot and I didn't know it?
機器會把你從內熔毀
The machine would melt you from the inside out.
請快走  先生
Please move along, sir.
好吧  我不是機器人  我不會有事
Okay, I'm not a robot, so I'll be fine.
什么
What?
-那是什么  -你的即刻氣場
- Oh, what's that? - Your temporal aura.
-那是什么  -請穿過門
- What's that? - Please, through the door.
取號
Take a ticket.
這難道是熟食店嗎  不要
What is this, a deli? No.
取號
Take a ticket.
這里只有我們兩個
There's only two of us in here.
取號
Take a ticket.
這是個錯誤  我不該來這里
This is a mistake! I shouldn't be here!
你好  你可能在說
Hey there! You're probably saying,
"這是個錯誤  我不該來這里"
"This is a mistake. I shouldn't even be here."
歡迎來到時間變異管理局
Welcome to the Time Variance Authority.
我是分鐘小姐
I'm Miss Minutes,
我的工作就是在你
and it's my job to catch you up
接受罪行審判前  讓你了解情況
before you stand trial for your crimes.
那我們就別再浪費一分鐘了
So let's not waste another minute.
坐好  把筆削尖  看看這個吧
Settle in, sharpen your pencils, and check this out.
很久以前  發生了牽涉甚廣的多元宇宙戰爭
Long ago, there was a vast multiversal war.
無數獨特的時間線彼此爭奪優勢地位
Countless unique timelines battled each other for supremacy,
幾乎導致了萬事萬物的
nearly resulting in the total destruction of...
徹底毀滅
...well, everything.
但之后  全知的時間守護者出現了
But then, the all-knowing Time-Keepers emerged,
通過將多元宇宙重新整理為
bringing peace by reorganizing
單一時間線  而帶來了和平
the multiverse into a single timeline,
也就是神圣時間線
the Sacred Timeline.
現在時間守護者們
Now, the Time-Keepers
為世上萬物保護保存
protect and preserve the proper flow of time
正常的時間流
for everyone and everything.
但有時  像你這樣的人
But sometimes, people like you
會偏離時間守護者創建的道路
veer off the path the Time-Keepers created.
我們稱這種人為時間異體
We call those Variants.
或許你發起了起義  或只是上班遲到了
Maybe you started an uprising, or were just late for work.
不管是怎么回事  偏離道路創造了關聯事件
Whatever it was, stepping off your path created a nexus event,
關聯
如果不加以管理  就可能瘋狂分支
which, left unchecked, could branch off into madness,
再次導致多元宇宙戰爭
leading to another multiversal war.
危險  多元宇宙
但別擔心
But, don't worry,
為了確保不會如此
to make sure that doesn't happen,
時間守護者創造了時管局和它了不起的員工們
the Time-Keepers created the TVA and all its incredible workers.
時管局已插手修復了你的錯誤
The TVA has stepped in to fix your mistake
并讓時間恢復到了原本應有的道路上
and set time back on its predetermined path.
而你因為自己的行為
Now that your actions have
在時間線上無容身之地了
left you without a place on the timeline,
所以你必須因自己的罪行受審
you must stand trial for your offenses.
坐好吧  我們會讓你馬上面見法官
So sit tight, and we'll get you in front of a judge in no time.
務必拿好你的排號
Just make sure you have your ticket,
一旦有接待者有空就會來見你
and you'll be seen by the next available attendant.
-時時刻刻  -永永遠遠
- For all time. - Always.
時間守護者  神圣時間線
Time-Keepers? The Sacred Timeline?
誰會相信這種蠢話
Who actually believes this bunkum?
排號  先生
Ticket, sir?
那人沒給我號  我跟他要了
That guy didn't give me a ticket. I tried to ask for one.
-請出示排號  先生  -我還跟他要了
- Ticket, sir! - I tried to ask that guy for a ticket!
先生
Sir...
你還沖我吼起來了嗎  蠢貨
What, you're raising your voice at me, bucket head?
謝謝您蒞臨時管局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
盡請對我們的服務做出評價
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.
洛基
第一季 第一集
法國  普羅旺斯地區艾克斯
追蹤者和時間衛隊響應了一樁常規關聯事件
The hunter and his Minutemen responded to a routine nexus event.
似乎他們到達時  遭到了伏擊
It appears that when they arrived, somebody got the jump on 'em.
還用說
You think?
是他
It's him.
是啊  看刺傷跟其他人一致
Yeah, stab wounds look consistent with the others.
尸體的位置
Positioning of the bodies
表明他們根本沒來得及反應
indicates they didn't know what the hell hit 'em.
重置設備也不見了
And reset charge is gone.
這是上周第六起襲擊了
That's the sixth attack in the last week.
據我們所知
That we know of.
放下武器
Wait, stand down! Stand down.
只是個孩子
It's just a kid.
不好意思
我朋友是個白癡
喂
Hey, yo!
我也會說時間線上的所有語言
混蛋
敲一下
Tap it.
你知道這是誰干的嗎
別擔心  那個魔鬼還怕我們呢
Don't worry, that devil's afraid of us.
我們會解決他的
We're gonna take care of him.
我們會讓你回你該去的地方
And we're gonna put you back where you belong.
那藍色...
那是怎么回事
爆炸藍莓口香糖
帶禮物來的魔鬼
Devil bearing gifts.
檢查它的時序年代
Go ahead and run this for sequence period
和即刻氣場痕跡
and any hints of temporal aura.
你知道我們查不到什么的
You know we won't get anything.
就試試嘛
Yeah, just give it a shot.
時間分支接近紅線了  我們得走了
The branch is nearing red line. We need to go.
好
Okay.
去外面等著
沒事的
It's okay.
進行重置
Set a reset charge.
長官  你會想看看這個
Sir, there's something you'll wanna see.
已被捕
下一案請上前
Next case, please.
勞菲森  時間異體L1130  洛基·勞菲森
Laufeyson. Variant L1130, AKA Loki Laufeyson,
被控時序違規7-20-89
is charged with sequence violation 7-20-89.
你是否認罪
How do you plead?
夫人  神不會懇求
Madam, a god doesn't plead.
這出啞劇還挺有意思
Look, this has been a very enjoyable pantomime,
但我現在想回家了
but I'd like to go home now.
你是否有罪  先生
Are you guilty or not guilty, sir?
我可是惡作劇之神  是的
Guilty of being the God of Mischief? Yes.
我是否覺得這一切無比乏味  是的
Guilty of finding all this incredibly tedious? Yes.
是否侵犯了神圣時間線
Guilty of a crime against the Sacred Timeline?
絕對沒有  你們抓錯了人
Absolutely not, you have the wrong person.
是嗎  那我們該抓誰去
Oh, really? And who should we have?
我懷疑是復仇者聯盟
I suspect, the Avengers.
我之所以能拿到宇宙魔方
You see, I only came into possession of the Tesseract
是因為他們穿越了時間
because they traveled through time,
肯定是為阻止我登天為神王
no doubt in a last-ditch effort to
而做出的最后一搏
stave off my ascent to God King.
好嚴重的指控
That's quite an accusation.
相信我  兩個托尼·斯塔克的古龍水味兒好明顯
Oh, believe me, you can smell the cologne of two Tony Starks.
你說什么時間罪犯  那你該去找他們
You speak of Time Criminals? It's they you should be after.
或許你可以給我指派一支特遣隊  再給我些資源
Perhaps you could provide me with a taskforce and resources,
我可以回去  替你們除掉他們
and I could return and eliminate them for you.
我們要說的不是復仇者聯盟
We're not here to talk about the Avengers.
-是嗎  -對
- Oh, no? - No.
他們做的事本就該發生  而你的逃跑不是
What they did was supposed to happen. You escaping was not.
這樣啊
Right.
"不該發生"  這誰說的
"Not supposed to happen"? According to whom?
時間守護者啊
The Time-Keepers?
時間守護者  這樣啊
Oh, the Time-Keepers. Right.
或許我該跟這些時間守護者  神對神地談談
Well, perhaps I should speak to these Time-Keepers, gods to gods.
抱歉  但他們很忙呢
I'm sorry, but they're quite busy.
是嗎  他們忙著干什么呢
Oh, they are? What are they doing?
決定正常的時間流
Dictating the proper flow of time.
這樣啊  好吧  那你是做什么的
I see. Right. And then what do you do?
按照他們的決定  決定正常的時間流
Dictate the proper flow of time according to their dictations.
你是否認罪
How do you plead?
我的確
Guilty...
做了這個
of this.
-怎么回事  -等等  都別說話
- What's going on? - Hang on. Everyone quiet.
-他是想用他的法力  夫人  -別催我
- He's trying to use his powers, ma'am. - Don't rush me.
該死  怎么不好使
Damn it! Why won't it work?
魔法嗎  那個在時管局不能用  勞菲森先生
Magic powers? They're no good in the TVA, Mr. Laufeyson.
本庭判你有罪  我判你被重置
The court finds you guilty, and I sentence you to be reset.
下一案請上前
Next case, please!
"重置"  那什么意思
"Reset"? What does that mean?
那很糟嗎  那什么意思
What, is it bad? What does it mean?
你們這些荒唐的官僚
You ridiculous bureaucrats
休想決定我的故事如何結局
will not dictate how my story ends!
不是你的故事  勞菲森先生  從來都不是
It's not your story, Mr. Laufeyson. It never was.
你根本想象不到我能做什么
You have no idea what I'm capable of!
我可能知道
I... I think I might.
他能做什么
Have an idea of what he's capable of.
上前
Approach the bench.
如果你在想我認為你在想的那事  那不是好主意
If you're thinking what I think you are, it's a bad idea.
好吧  我只是跟著直覺走
Okay, I'm just chasing a hunch.
如果出了任何岔子  都怪在你頭上
Anything goes sideways, it's on you.
好  我覺得我總在仰視你
Okay. I feel like I'm always looking up to you.
我喜歡  很恰當
I like it. It's appropriate.
你是誰
And who are you?
我要把這里燒成灰
I'm gonna burn this place to the ground.
我帶你去我的辦公桌  你從那里開始燒吧
I'll show you where my desk is, you can start there.
看看吧
Have a look.
美麗的家園
Home sweet home.
這里不是沒有魔法嗎
I thought there was no magic here.
是沒有
There isn't.
那不是真的
That's not real.
是的  很遺憾  各種文件也是真的
It is, and, unfortunately, so is all the paperwork.
但可以給你點火做火絨  來吧
Good tinder for your fire, though. Come on.
這地方是個噩夢
This place is a nightmare.
那是另一個部門了
That's another department.
那個部門我樂意幫你燒光
Now that department I'll help you burn down.
對了  我是莫比烏斯特工
I'm Agent Mobius, by the way.
你是要帶我去個什么地方殺掉嗎
Are you taking me somewhere to kill me?
不是  我才帶你離開那個處境
No. That's where you just were.
我的帶你去個地方談談
I'm taking you some place to talk.
我不喜歡談談
I don't like to talk.
但你喜歡撒謊  你剛剛還撒了謊
But you do like to lie, which you just did.
因為我們都知道  你很喜歡說話
Because we both know you love to talk.
說啊說啊
Talkie-talkie.
你在這里干多久了
How long have you been here?
我不知道  不好說
I don't know. It's hard to say,
時管局的時間流逝不一樣
time passes differently here in the TVA.
-什么意思  -你會了解的
- What does that mean? - You'll catch up.
所以你是時管局勇敢盡心的員工之一嗎
So, you're part of the TVA's courageous and dedicated workforce?
對
Yes.
-你們是時間守護者創造的  -對
- You were created by the Time- Keepers. - Yep.
-目的是保護神圣時間線  -對
- To protect the Sacred Timeline. - Correct.
那好笑嗎
Is that funny?
你們的小俱樂部
The idea that your little club
能代表三個太空蜥蜴
decides the fate of trillions of people
決定浩瀚宇宙中無數人的命運
across all of existence at the behest of three space lizards,
是的  這很好笑
yes, it's funny.
這好荒唐
It's absurd.
不是說你不喜歡說話嗎
I thought you didn't like to talk.
你先請
After you.
我要說
For the record,
這里感覺真像個用來殺人的房間
this really does feel like a killing-me kind of a room.
不怎么信任人  是吧
Not big on trust, are you?
孩子和狗才會信任
Trust is for children and dogs.
你只能信任一個人
There's only one person you can trust.
你自己嗎  我喜歡
Yourself? I like it.
印T恤衫吧
Slap it on a T-shirt.
如果時管局真的監管一切時間
If the TVA truly oversees all of time,
我們怎么會此前都沒聽說過你們
how have I never heard of you until now?
因為你此前不需要聽說
'Cause you've never needed to.
你一直生活在你的既定道路里
You've always lived within your set path.
我是生活在我選擇的道路里
I live within whatever path I choose.
當然了  好了  來坐吧
Sure you do. Okay, come have a seat.
我說了  時管局的時間運行不一樣
I told you, time moves differently in the TVA.
來坐吧
Come on, sit down.
我們開始吧
Let's get into this.
來啊  坐吧
Go on, have a seat.
要是眼神能殺人
If looks could kill.
你想要我怎么樣
What do you want from me?
先配合一下吧
Well, let's start with a little cooperation.
我不擅長
Not my forte.
是嗎
Really?
哪怕是討好你打算背叛的強者時嗎
Even when you're wooing someone powerful you intend to betray?
得了
Come on.
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
或許我想了解呢
Maybe I'd like to learn.
我專門追蹤危險的時間異體
I specialize in the pursuit of dangerous Variants.
比如我嗎
Like myself?
不  是特別危險的時間異體
No, particularly dangerous Variants.
你就是個小貓咪
You're just a little pussycat.
我要問你一組問題
I got a set of questions for you.
你要誠實回答
You answer them honestly,
那樣的話  我或許能滿足你的一些愿望
and then maybe I can give you something you want.
你想離開這里  是吧
You wanna get out of here, right?
嗯  那就從這里開始
Yeah, so we'll start there.
如果你回去了  打算怎么做
Should you return, what are you gonna do?
-完成我開啟的大業  -那是什么
- Finish what I started. - Which is?
奪取我的王位
Claim my throne.
你想做國王嗎
You wanna be king?
我不是想做  我生來就是
I don't want to be, I was born to be.
我知道  但具體是什么的國王
I know, but king of what exactly?
你不會理解的
You wouldn't understand.
說來試試
Try me.
米德加德
Midgard.
就是地球
AKA Earth.
好  你成為米德加德的國王了  然后呢
All right. Now you're the king of Midgard, then what?
幸福永遠了嗎
Happily ever after?
阿斯加德  九大王國
Asgard, the Nine Realms.
-宇宙嗎  -是的
- Space? - Space?
宇宙很大  那是不錯的功績
Space is big. That'd be a nice feather in your cap.
"洛基  宇宙之王"
"Loki, the King of Space."
你敢嘲笑我
Mock me if you dare.
不  我沒
No, I'm not.
真的  我其實是你的粉絲
Honestly, I'm actually a fan. Yeah.
我就是在想
And I guess I'm wondering why
你這么有潛力的人  怎么就想做統治者
does someone with so much range just wanna rule?
我會讓人們輕松的
I would've made it easy for them.
人們喜歡輕松
People like easy.
第一個  也是最壓迫的謊言
The first and most oppressive lie ever uttered
就是自由之歌
was the song of freedom.
怎么說
How's that one go?
對幾乎所有生靈
For nearly every living thing,
選擇帶來羞恥  不確定和后悔
choice breeds shame and uncertainty and regret.
每條道路上都有岔路
There's a fork in every road,
可人們總走錯路
yet the wrong path always taken.
很好
Good. Yeah.
你說"幾乎所有生靈"
You said "Nearly every living thing,"
那么你應該是不算在內咯
so I'm guessing you don't fall into that category?
時間守護者建造了驚人的奇景
The Time-Keepers have built quite the circus,
而且小丑也完美地扮演了自己的角色
and I see the clowns are playing their parts to perfection.
這么愛用比喻  我喜歡
Big metaphor guy. I love it.
讓你聽上去特別聰明
Makes you sound super smart.
我就是聰明
I am smart.
我知道
I know.
好
Okay.
這是什么
What is this?
你壯舉的抽樣  容我來
A sampling of your greatest hits, if I may.
如果你們不介意
If it's all the same to you...
我現在想來一杯
I'll have that drink now.
不用
No.
我記得  我當時也在  還有嗎
And I remember. I was there. Anything else?
真有趣  生來的統治者  你輸了好多次
It's funny, for someone born to rule, you sure do lose a lot.
甚至可以說這是你的天性
You might even say it's in your nature.
上一個對我說這種話的人
You know, things didn't turn out so well
下場可不怎么好
for the last person who said that to me.
嗯  菲爾·科爾森
Oh, yeah, Phil Coulson.
不
No!
復仇者聯盟不是為了
Didn't the Avengers come together
給他復仇而團結一心  擊敗了你嗎
to literally avenge him by defeating you?
對于一個死人算不上什么安慰了
Little solace to a dead man.
你喜歡傷人嗎
Do you enjoy hurting people?
讓他們覺得渺小
Making them feel small?
讓他們感到恐懼
Making them feel afraid?
-你的游戲嚇不倒我  -讓他們覺得弱小
- Your games don't frighten me. - Making them feel little?
我知道我是什么人
I know what I am.
-殺人犯嗎  -解放者
- A murderer? - A liberator.
解放了眼球吧
Of eyeballs, maybe.
看那笑容  你很喜歡那么做
Look at that smile. You are enjoying that.
你喜歡傷害他們嗎
Did you enjoy hurting them?
我不需要玩這種游戲  我可是神
I don't have to play this game. I'm a god.
什么神來著  惡作劇之神吧
Of what, again? Mischief, right?
嗯  我可不覺得這算什么惡作劇
Yeah. I don't see anything very mischievous about this.
是啊  你是看不出吧
No, I don't suppose you do.
我們談談你的逃跑吧
Let's talk about your escapes.
你很擅長做壞事
You're really good at doing awful things,
然后逃掉
and then just getting away.
沒辦法  我就是個喜歡惡作劇的頑皮鬼
What can I say? I'm a mischievous scamp.
這是我最喜歡的之一
This is one of my favorites.
這里是駕駛艙  威廉·A·斯考特機長
From the flight deck, Captain William A. Scott,
西北東方航空305航班  按時飛往西雅圖
Northwest Orient Airlines 305, on schedule to land in Seattle.
今天的飛行時間  約...
Flight time today, approximately...
波本和蘇打水嗎
Bourbon and soda?
謝謝
Thank you.
不客氣
Absolutely.
還需要我為您做什么嗎  先生
Is there anything else I can do for you, sir?
那就看看吧
I suppose we'll find out, won't we?
-小姐  -是  庫珀先生
- Uh, Miss? - Yes, Mr. Cooper?
你最好看看那張字條
You might want to take a look at that note.
我有枚炸彈
I have a bomb.
我看不出這有什么關系...
I fail to see how this has any relevance or bearing on...
別  精彩的部分在這里
No. This is the good part.
改天再見了
See you again someday.
哥哥  海姆達爾  你們最好準備好了
Brother, Heimdall, you better be ready.
真不敢相信你是DB·庫珀  拜托
I can't believe you were D.B. Cooper. Come on!
我當時還年輕  打賭輸給了托爾
I was young, and I lost a bet to Thor.
我插手這樣的人間事務時  時管局怎么不管
Where was the TVA when I was meddling with these affairs of men?
我們當時也在  在神圣時間線上沖浪呢
We were right there with you, just surfing that Sacred Timeline.
所以那就得到了時間守護者的認同嗎
So that had the Time-Keepers' seal of approval, did it?
說起來倒不算是
Well, I wouldn't think of it
認同或不認同
in terms of approval and disapproval.
那是...
That's sort of a...
我們繼續說逃跑吧
Let's get back to escapes...
以及心理問題
...and a little psychobabble.
你覺得你究竟在逃離什么
What is it that you think that you're really running from?
夠了
Enough.
回籠子里咯
Back in your cage.
看  我也會玩狠的
See, I can play the heavy keys, too.
我站起來只是有話說
I was just standing up to make a point.
抱歉  請吧
I'm sorry, go ahead.
現在做就失去意義了
It won't be as meaningful now.
好吧  那坐著別動
Okay, well, stay seated.
我想做什么就做什么
I'll do what I want to do!
當然
Sure.
你到底想怎么樣
What exactly is it that you want?
我想要你坦誠你這樣做的原因
I want you to be honest about why you do what you do.
騙子
Liar.
我是認真的
I'm serious.
我只想更深入地了解
All I seek is a deeper understanding
可怕的惡作劇之神
of the fearsome God of Mischief.
洛基的動機是什么
What makes Loki tick?
-我知道這是什么地方  -什么地方
- I know what this place is. - What is it?
這是個幻象
It's an illusion.
是弱者
It's a cruel,
為了激發恐懼而精心策劃的殘忍詭計
elaborate trick conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
孤注一擲  試圖掌控一切
A desperate attempt at control.
你們招搖賣弄
Now, you all parade about
仿佛你們是宇宙力量的神圣仲裁者
as if you're the divine arbiters of power in the universe.
-我們的確是  -才不是
- We are. - You're not.
我的選擇是我自己的
My choices are my own.
你的選擇是你自己的  很好  就從這入手
Your choice is your own. Good, let's go with that.
這應該能讓你激動起來
I think this one's gonna fire you up.
自由的光鮮誘惑削減了你們人生的樂趣
The bright lure of freedom diminishes your life's joy
讓你們發狂地追逐權力
in a mad scramble for power...
確實
Precisely.
我本來...
I was...
我現在仍然快要得到我應得的一切
I am on the verge of acquiring everything I am owed,
如果我得到了  都是因為我的努力
and when I do, it'll be because I did it.
不是因為這是理所當然的
Not because it was supposed to happen.
也不是因為你或時間變異管理局
Or because you or the Time Variance Authority,
或不管你們自稱什么  允許我得到
or whatever it is you call yourselves, allowed me to.
老實說  你很可悲
Honestly, you're pathetic.
你無關緊要
You're an irrelevance.
只是一條彎路
A detour.
我攀登的注腳
A footnote to my ascent.
你說完了嗎
You finished?
你要開始嚴肅對待了
You're gonna start taking things seriously.
如果你那時沒有撿起宇宙魔方
If you hadn't picked up the Tesseract,
你就會被關進阿斯加德的牢房
you would have been taken to a cell on Asgard.
洛基
Loki.
你好  母親
Hello, Mother.
你為我驕傲嗎
Have I made you proud?
求求你  別讓事情變得更糟
Please don't make this worse.
這是什么
What is this?
這是胡扯  又是幻術  這根本沒發生過
This is nonsense, more tricks. This never even happened.
沒發生在你身上
Not to you.
還沒有
Not yet.
時管局不只知道你的過去
Look, the TVA doesn't just know your whole past,
我們還知道你的一生  注定要發生的事
we know your whole life, how it's all meant to be.
把這看作安慰
Think of it as comforting.
這太荒謬了
This is absurd.
那我也不是你母親嗎
And am I not your mother?
不是
You're not.
你總能看透一切  卻看不透自己
Always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
然后黑暗精靈襲擊了宮殿
And then the Dark Elves attack the palace,
你以為你讓他們去找托爾了
and you think you send them to Thor.
走左邊的樓梯吧
You might wanna take the stairs to the left.
其實你把他們指向了...
But instead, you send them...
我絕不會告訴你
I'll never tell.
你把她關在哪了  她在哪里
Where do you have her? Where is she?
你讓他們找到了她
You lead them right to her.
我不相信  你撒謊  這不是真的
I don't believe you. You're lying. It's not true.
這就是真的
It is true.
那才是正常的時間流
That's the proper flow of time,
它一次又一次發生
and it happens again and again and again
因為理應如此
because it's supposed to,
因為必須如此
because it has to.
-時管局確保了  -她在哪里
- The TVA makes sure of it. - Where is she?
不如你告訴我  你喜歡傷人嗎
Now why don't you tell me, do you enjoy hurting people?
-我不信你  -你享受殺戮嗎
- I don't believe you. - Do you enjoy killing?
-我會殺了你  -就像你殺了你媽媽
- I'll kill you. - What? Like you did your mother?
抱歉  時間扭轉器只讓你循環
Sorry, the Time Twister just loops you,
對椅子不起作用
not the furniture.
你并非生來注定為王  洛基
You weren't born to be king, Loki.
而是注定帶來痛苦  苦難和死亡
You were born to cause pain and suffering and death.
現在如此  過去如此  將來也如此
That's how it is, that's how it was, that's how it will be.
都是為了讓其他人能成就最好的自己
All so that others can achieve their best versions of themselves.
這是什么地方
What is this place?
來吧
Come on.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我的工作  你的工作是來打斷嗎
My job. Is it yours to interrupt?
有情況
We have a situation.
總是有情況
There's always a situation.
哪都別去
Don't go anywhere.
正進行到精彩的地方  情緒高昂
It was just getting good. Spirited.
-和那個時間異體對話是個錯誤  -那是你的看法
- Talking to that Variant is a mistake. - That's your position.
-他應該被重置  -我的觀點與你相反
- He should be reset! - I take the opposite...
你認為所有人都該被重置  我剛取得進展
You think everyone should be reset. I'm getting good stuff!
我們又失去了一支隊伍
We lost another unit.
洛基  我們明天再完成  接著...
Okay, Loki, I think we can finish up tomorrow and just pick it...
惡作劇的頑皮鬼
Mischievous scamp.
可惜我不感到意外
Wish I could say I was surprised.
-誰讓你打斷了我們  -我  怪我咯
- Yeah, I wish you hadn't interrupted us. - Me? It's my fault?
聽著  他一定沒走遠
Look, he can't have gotten very far.
分頭行動  見人就刪
Split up. Prune on sight.
不  不準刪除或重置  他仍能幫我們
No, no pruning, no resetting. He can still help us!
我知道你
I know you.
你是那個帶著藍盒子的罪犯
You're that criminal with the blue box.
你叫什么
What's your name?
凱西
Casey.
把宇宙魔方給我  否則我把你當魚一樣開膛  凱西
Give me the Tesseract, or I'll gut you like a fish, Casey.
魚是什么
What's a fish?
魚是什么東西
你怎么會不知道魚是什么
How do you not know what a fish is?
我這輩子一直坐在桌子后面
I've lived my entire life behind a desk.
那又如何
Well, what difference does it make?
我想知道我面對的是什么威脅  然后再照辦
I wanna know exactly what I'm being threatened with before I comply.
死亡  凱西  暴力的痛苦的死亡
Death, Casey. Violent, painful death.
好好好  我照辦
Okay, okay. I comply, I comply.
我照辦  天啊
I comply. Jeez!
是這個
This it?
什么
What?
無限寶石
Infinity Stones?
你怎么
How...
你怎么拿到它們的
How do you have these?
我們有很多
Oh, We actually get a lot of those.
對  有人用這些石頭當鎮紙
Yeah. Some of the guys use them as paperweights.
有些人吧
Some of 'em.
這是宇宙里最強大的力量嗎
Is this the greatest power in the universe?
你差點打到我
Oh, you almost hit me!
太過分了
That's so messed up.
分頭行動  搜查下面的大廳
Split up. Check the lower concourse.
我不原諒你
I do not forgive you.
我愛你們  我的兒子
I love you, my sons.
記住這地方
Remember this place.
家園
Home.
洛基  我曾非常看重你
Loki, I thought the world of you.
我以為我們能永遠并肩戰斗
I thought we were gonna fight side by side forever.
或許你也沒那么壞  弟弟
Maybe you're not so bad after all, brother.
或許吧
Maybe not.
謝謝
Thank you.
如果你真在這里  我或許還會抱抱你
If you were here, I might even give you a hug.
我在這兒
I'm here.
不死
Undying?
你措辭該更小心點的
You should choose your words more carefully.
你
You...
永遠不會成為
will never be...
神
a god.
文件結束
什么事這么好笑
What's so funny?
光榮的使命
Glorious purpose.
停
Stop...
下來
It.
停下來
Stop it!
St... Stop it...
下來  停下來
It... Stop it...
停  來下  停下來
Stop... I... St... Sto... St...
那人一直念叨著要把我變成魚
And this guy kept saying he was gonna turn me into a fish,
不知道那是什么
whatever that is,
然后他們出現了  刪了我的推車
and then they show up and just prune my cart,
所以我什么都做不了
so there was nothing I could have done.
你在這兒啊
There you are.
那個從你眼前溜走的那個時間異體
You know, that Variant you had got away.
洛基
Loki?
無處可逃了哦
Nowhere left to run.
我不能回去  對吧
I can't go back, can I?
不能回我的時間線
Back to my timeline.
我不喜歡傷害人
I don't enjoy hurting people.
我
I...
我不喜歡
I don't enjoy it.
我那樣做也是無奈
I do it because I have to,
因為我當時不得不那樣做
because I've had to.
跟我詳細說說
Okay, explain that to me.
因為那是幻象的一部分
Because it's part of the illusion.
是弱者為了激發恐懼
It's the cruel, elaborate trick
而精心策劃的殘忍詭計
conjured by the weak to inspire fear.
孤注一擲  試圖掌控一切
A desperate play for control.
你相當了解你自己嘛
You do know yourself.
一個惡棍
A villain.
我不這么看
That's not how I see it.
你想用它
You try to use that?
用過幾次
Oh, several times.
就連無限寶石在這里都沒用了
Even an Infinity Stone is useless here.
時管局如此強大
The TVA is formidable.
從我的經驗來看  沒錯
That's been my experience.
聽著  我給不了你救贖
Listen, I can't offer you salvation,
但我也許可以給你更好的
but maybe I can offer you something better.
一名在逃時間異體一直在殺害我們的時間衛隊
A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
你們需要惡作劇之神協助你們阻止他
And you need the God of Mischief to help you stop him?
沒錯
That's right.
那為什么選我
Why me?
我們要抓捕的時間異體是
The Variant we're hunting is...
你
you.
你說什么
I beg your pardon?
俄克拉荷馬  薩林那
時間特征是3000年初
Time signature is early third millennium.
絕對不屬于這個時代
Definitely anachronistic.
石油
Oil.
應該是哪個混蛋找到了一臺時間機器
I think some jackass found himself a time machine,
回來過去  想要暴富
came back here to get rich.
要我們散開找他嗎  長官
Should we fan out and look for him, sir?
不了  不值得我們寫報告
Nah. It's not worth the paperwork.
刪了它  我們撤  進行重置
Just prune it. Let's bail. Set a charge.
等等  那邊有人
Wait. Someone's out there.
去看看
Check it out.
趴下
Get down!
謝謝您蒞臨時管局
Thanks for visiting the TVA.
盡請對我們的服務做出評價
Don't hesitate to let us know how we're doing.